Setumadhava Giridhar Kathawate

Product Designer | Problem Solver

206-739-4983 setugk8@gmail.com Atlanta, GA <u>www.setumadhava.com</u>

About

Product designer having over 3 years of experience (Industry + Start-up) in designing products, seeking opportunities to help organizations solve complex user and business problems through the human-centered design process and grow as a design leader.

Skills

Research - User interviews, Surveys, Contextual inquiry, User journey maps, Use case flows, Personas, Usability studies.

Design - Sketching, Wireframes, Interactive and web (HTML/CSS) prototyping, Visual design.

Miscellaneous - Running design studios and critiques, Data synthesis, Cross-functional collaboration, Problem scoping and prioritization, Writing, Hypothesis driven design, Critical thinking.

Experience

UX DESIGNER II, THE HOME DEPOT (VIA SYNERGIS)

APR 2018 - PRESENT

Leading the full-stack UX efforts to design enterprise apps for Home Depot's Direct Fulfillment Center leaders and employees. The goal is to help them make faster and better decisions so that customers' orders are shipped efficiently on time.

Key Accomplishment: Worked in a very fast-paced environment with partners who were not familiar or comfortable with the UX Design process and successfully designed apps that significantly improved the experience for the end-users and in the process gained the stakeholder trust.

UX DESIGNER, UW MEDICINE (VIA CREATIVE CIRCLE)

DEC 2017 - MAR 2018

Designed web and mobile experiences as a part of UW Medicine's website redesign efforts.

Key Accomplishment: Owned the responsibility and delivered 14 high-fidelity, production-ready web and mobile screen mockups in 2 days, after the contracted design agency failed to deliver the designs on-time. As a result, there was no delay in the project timelines.

CO-FOUNDER AND PRODUCT DESIGNER, EVENTOSAUR

MAR 2015 - PRESENT

Leading a distributed team of designers and non-designers to build a SaaS product to solve the problem of order, inventory and team management for event vendors in India.

Key Accomplishment: Co-founded a profitable event-planning start-up and worked remotely while in grad school to design a web-app that solved the problem of vendor discovery and reduced the complexity in traditional event planning for millennials in India.

UX DESIGNER, PREMERA BLUE CROSS (VIA FILTER DIGITAL)

MAY 2017 - DEC 2017

Led the UX efforts to design a Provider Search tool to help Premera's customers confidently find the providers or facilities covered by their insurance plan.

Key Accomplishment: Average customer satisfaction score went up from 2.8 to 4.1 (on a scale of 1-5) after shipping the new search experience.

Education

MASTER'S IN HUMAN CENTERED DESIGN AND ENGINEERING

SEP 2015 - MAR 2017

The University of Washington, Seattle; GPA 3.92/4.0

Relevant Courses: User-Centered Design, Usability Studies, Data Science for UX Researchers, Visual Communication, Interaction Design and Prototyping.

BACHELOR'S IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING

AUG 2006 - JUN 2010

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Bangalore, India; GPA 6.9/10.0

Awards

BEST GRADUATE CAPSTONE PROJECT - PUMP IT UP

JUN 2017

University of Washington, Seattle

Explored design solutions to reduce water waste in Indian homes by designing an Android app + IOT system that provides contextual information and better control over existing water systems to the residents.